losif V.

Software Engineer

London, (UK)

in iosify 🞧 iosify 🚵 iosify

SUMMARY

I am a Senior Software Engineer with extensive experience in developing end-to-end projects using Node.js and Laravel. I prioritize writing clean, maintainable code to ensure ease of maintenance and quick onboarding for junior developers. With a natural curiosity and a commitment to continuous learning, I am always exploring new technologies and methodologies to enhance my skills and contribute effectively to my team and stakeholders.

SKILLS

Languages Frameworks Admin

Node.jsTypescriptPHPLaravelExpressServerlessAWSTerraformCI / CDSoliditybashHardhatDockerShell Scripting

Currently learning

Java NextJS T3 Stack

WORK EXPERIENCE (4)

Aug 2018 - Current

Contractor Software Engineer at

Provided contractor services through my own LTD, Casa4, in between other roles. The following is a list of the most notable projects, specializing in Laravel and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment.

- Artetra: As an acting CTO, I was responsible with converting business requirements into project features by overseeing the application architecture. I managed a team of 3-4 developers and provided them with necessary assistance.
- ElectroRent: Developed and maintained Laravel code to fix bugs and add new features for a tool-renting platform.
- Aliat Optic: Designed and developed an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB. This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal maintenance, demonstrating reliability and efficiency.
- Hurlingham Club: Led the migration of systems to internal servers, resolving various DevOps issues.
- TicketTailor: Improved the API of a large ticketing application by fixing bugs and adding new features.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Node.js, React, AWS Lambda, MySQL, Terraform, AWS, VueJS, NextJS, CLI, Bash

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer at

Contributed to the development of a cloud-based compliance management system, enhancing compliance tracking and reporting capabilities.

- Developed the main API of the system and contributed to designing the ecosystem's serverless architecture, leading to a robust and scalable solution.
- Created a reporting application that enabled non-technical stakeholders to preview any key metrics.
- Also built a bespoke real-time caching system that stores processed relational data in a NoSQL database.
 The purpose of this was to vastly increase the speed of the system and reduce the load on the database.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Software Engineer at

Designed and developed main applications and maintained AWS infrastructure, contributing to the company's mission of improving skin health.

- Led the migration from a NoSQL database to a relational database, resulting in an 11x speed increase without affecting the frontend or user experience.
- Green Handwight Strategies Green Strategies Green Strategies Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

Application Developer / Dev-Ops at

Sole Backend Engineer responsible for designing, developing, and supporting client applications, driving business growth.

- Developed and maintained nationwide educational platforms, enhancing the learning experience for thousands of users.
- Built a comprehensive financial management application with Laravel and Vue, streamlining financial operations.
- Managed all DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup on Forge, ensuring reliable and efficient deployment processes.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, MySql, VueJS

PROJECTS (2) -

CLI Path

https://iosifv.github.io/cli-path/

Simple CLI tool to search paths on google maps (Serverless Framework, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS)

Casa4 website

An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes (Hugo, Terraform, Cloudfront, AWS, GHA)

EDUCATION (2)

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

INTERESTS

Hobbies

Chess HiFi Music

Motorcycles Photography